extraordinarily dangerous.
Unfortunately, Iran has proven to be a
pretty clever adversary. You can't do
that kind of invasion with a couple of
thousand troops. You need a couple of
hundred thousand troops. They do want to
die. The Ayatollah knew he was going to
get hit. He sat there and I think he
thought he was going to go up to
paradise and find his 72 virgins. The
Iranians have been reactive to this, not
proactive. There has to be a response.
You can't just say, "Well, you know
what? We're in existential threat to the
Israelis. So, of course the Israelis are
going to have to bomb us." There's never
been a guarantee to defeat evil, but
there is one guarantee. If you don't
stand up to it, you're going to lose.
"Please help us bomb Iran. Please help
us bomb Iran. [music] Please help us
bomb Iran." And the president's always
said, "No." President Trump was duped by
Benjamin Netanyahu, and now we're in a
war that we cannot [music] win. I I
don't think I've ever seen a gathering
of more spineless people in my entire
life.
For all the talk of Vice President JD
Vance being marginalized by the war in
Iran, he could play a defining role in
ending it. The Iranians say they don't
trust the president's chief negotiator,
Stephen Witkoff and Jared Kushner, and
will not only talk to him. And that has
now kick-started the blame game for a
war that's becoming more complicated,
expensive, and unpopular by the day.
Benjamin Netanyahu, he says, oversold
Trump on the chances of an easy victory
and a swift uprising, neither of which
look close, if they're still possible at
all. According to the Vice President,
everything the US is doing now is to
prevent a drawn-out war.
We've accomplished the gross majority of
our military objectives. I think you can
make a good argument we've accomplished
all of our military objectives. The
president's going to keep at it for a
little while longer to ensure that we
once we leave, we don't have to do this
again for a very, very long time. The
problem is, as it always has been, that
the objectives are unclear and
ever-changing. Trump says he's
negotiating with a new regime in
waiting, but we don't know who that is.
Thousands of US Marines are now in the
region with special forces and
paratroopers on the way. They're
reportedly preparing for a ground
operation that could take weeks. There's
talk of seizing and occupying Hog Island
to choke off the oil exports which keep
the Iranian economy alive. The Wall
Street Journal says Trump is weighing up
a Hollywood-worthy raid on Iran's
uranium involving diggers, nuclear
scientists, and thousands of troops
behind enemy lines. Poly Markets says
there's now a 70% chance the US forces
will enter Iran by the end of April and
up with
a 20% in just 2 days on a $54 million
market. Anyone who's paid any attention
to big market moves relating to this war
and this White House will know exactly
why that's worthy of our attention. And
running in parallel to all of this is
the ongoing escalation by America's
partner in the war. Israel is expanding
its invasion of Lebanon raising fears of
a scorched-earth campaign modeled on the
Gaza war. The IDF is facing intensifying
criticism for several attacks which
appear to have targeted journalists.
J.D. Vance may want a swift end to the
war in Iran as do the majority of
American people. There's currently no
indication they're going to get it.
To debate this I'm joined by Amotz
Kimmel, retired US Army Brigadier
General,
I'm I'm in Dane who's the author of Nine
Lives, My Time as MI6's
top spy inside Al-Qaeda, and Doron
Spielman, reservist IDF spokesman and
author of When the Stones Speak. Well,
welcome to all of you. Uh General
Kimmel, welcome back to Uncensored.
Every time we we talk in this war, it
seems to have escalated at the same rate
that President Trump and others try to
reassure us it's over and America has
already won. So, forgive me if I'm a
little bit confused sitting here in
London. Um
where are we with this war? Because from
where I sit, uh it's not over. The
Straits of Hormuz remain pretty well
closed. The attacks on the Gulf states
by Iran continue.
Uh there is enormous economic damage
from a month of the world's oil and gas
being held up along with the world's
fertilizer.
Uh, and uh, the president of the United
States is now committing a lot of troops
to the region and the briefings that the
papers are getting is [snorts] that he
is planning potentially
some sort of land invasion, which I have
to say again as I've been saying for a a
while now, that is completely contrary
to everything that Donald Trump
campaigned on. The one thing he
reassured his supporters was I will not
take America into any more senseless,
expensive wars in the Middle East and I
definitely won't put boots on the
ground. Here we are.
What do you make of it?
Well, first of all, you asked about 10
questions made by 10 statements. So, let
me get
first focus
>> Yeah, as much time as you like, General.
No, I'm [clears throat] I'm just going
to say let's remain focused on what I
believe either are or should have been
the objectives of this war. We went into
negotiations with the Iranians to do
three things.
Uh, end their nuclear program, end their
ballistic missile program, end their
proxy program. We were unable to achieve
that at the bargaining table, so we've
taken it to the battlefield. Uh, I think
that we've heard a lot of noise, a lot
of chatter, a lot of flak over the last
few weeks, but I certainly hope those
remain our core interests. And if those
remain our core interests, and candidly
the core interests of countries around
the world to include Great Britain,
uh, no, we haven't achieved our
objectives yet nor nor should we be
discussing off-ramps at this point.
Okay, but I my sense is that Donald
Trump would love an off-ramp if he could
claim any kind of legitimate victory
that gets him out of this because he
knows that, never mind anything else,
politically as he edges nearer to the
midterm elections, this is proving
incredibly unpopular. All the polls
[snorts] show that. Um, and I think that
for that reason alone, coupled with the
economic mayhem it's causing, it it
makes no sense to a businessman like
Donald Trump, a deal maker, to allow
this to continue for months and months
and months. And yet, I don't see how he
can stop it if the Iranians have worked
out that it's the economic part of this
war that they're currently winning.
No, I agree with you. Uh, first of all,
I don't think Donald Trump cares about
the midterms. He's already accepted them
as lost. Uh, even if they were won by
the Democrats, uh, the fact remains is
that nothing is going to get done uh, in
the United States Congress, whether the
Republicans still in charge or whether
the Democrats are in charge. Our
legislative body seems to be generally
irrelevant.
Uh, but look, I think that Donald Trump
now recognizes that the advice he took
or the or the orders that he issued are
not achieving the results uh, he wanted.
Unfortunately, Iran has proven to be a
pretty clever
uh, adversary. The Iranian the
uh, Israelis went for regime
decapitation, the Americans went for uh,
blow up as much stuff as possible, uh,
and the Iranians kind of did a jujitsu
move and said, "Okay, we're going to
move down to the Strait of Hormuz. If
you want to do regime decapitation,
we're going to do economic
decapitation."
As recent say, old dead Carl Clausewitz,
um,
he he had some great lines and one of
them is, "After a war starts, it takes
on its own character." And while this
president may have hoped for a quick and
easy victory as he had in Venezuela or a
negotiated settlement as he had in
Syria,
uh, this war has definitely taken on a
character of its own. And before I I go
to our two other very patient guests,
thank you to both of you.
Just one final question purely on the
military reality of any kind of ground
invasion. Because if it seems to be the
case, the only way to guarantee getting
the enriched uranium, which is believed
to be buried
way below the ground and heavily
protected.
If the only way to do that is with
ground forces,
is it not going to be incredibly
hazardous
to do that in a country like Iran when
they believe that regime change is
absolutely on the mind certainly of the
Israelis and probably quite a few people
in the Trump administration, too. In
other words, they have little to lose.
Uh that if America was to put ground
forces down, potentially with IDF and we
don't know, um is that not a very
dangerous mission, General?
Extraordinarily dangerous. Uh
these two gentlemen to my right uh don't
remember what you and I do, which is a
1979 mission to try to get the American
hostages out of Tehran. Uh that was an
absolute go to uh
I'll leave it at that. Yeah. Uh
but unfortunately, when you also not
only have a tough target, but it's the
your mission is being bleated out by
every broadsheet like the Wall Street
Journal and the New York Times, makes
life kind of difficult. So,
um I I simply think that that may be
again to use another trope, a bridge too
far at this point unless we pull some
real magic out of our house hats. And I
don't think we're going to be quote
invading or conducting an invasion. Uh
that brings to mind of your audience
another attack into Iraq to go up to
Baghdad. You can't do that kind of
invasion with a couple of thousand
troops. You need a couple of hundred
thousand troops. So, what I see those
ground troops being used for primarily
is short uh quick operations. Probably
no further in than the littoral to go
against the speed boats, the the the
mine factories, the missile factories
along the beaches.
Maybe even a dumb idea like Card Island.
Although I think the better way for Card
Island is just take out the electricity.
That way you can quickly turn it back on
when you need it.
I mean the problem and I'll come to all
the guests now. Doreen Speilman, the
problem here
is that Donald Trump has kind of
signaled everything that America may do.
He does it on a kind of every few hours
basis on social media.
>> and then he changes it two hours later.
Right. Right. And and the problem Doreen
Speilman is, you know, I can remember
watching
uh movies about the code breakers in
World War where there were whole teams
of people whose job it was to crack
sophisticated codes that the Germans
were leaving. For example, uh planning
their military operation. The Iranians
don't need any code breakers cuz they've
got the President of the United States
just broadcasting it all. So, you know,
they know that there may be an attack on
Hog, for example. They know that the
Americans may do XYZ because Trump keeps
saying that's what they may do. Is that
apart from anything else, is that is it
sensible?
Look, these are all the million dollar
questions how we're going to look back
at President Trump, you know, 100 years
from now. I can say this that he's
definitely knocking off balance
a a lot of terror regimes throughout the
world, including Venezuela. I think he's
sending a different message than has
been sent. It's not the typical
diplomatic message. This is kind of the
Trump deal maker where he comes in and
we've seen it multiple times when he
offers with one hand a carrot and with
the other hand if it's not taken, he's
got Marines moving in and I'm not sure
that it's the incorrect way. I think
we'll know when this is over, but I do
Pierce, kind of want to zoom out a
little bit. I think, you know, this is
not a new story. I think we need to kind
of take a few steps back here. This is a
story
that I can say as a Jew who's, you know,
we're going to be celebrating Passover
in two nights, it goes back to the
Passover story. This It's really a
question, are we going to, you know,
stand up against oppression? Are we
going to make a move that there's no
guarantee what we're going to do, but we
have a chance at changing the paradigm,
or are we just going to accept, okay,
you know, we're slaves, we're oppressed,
and we're going to allow a terrorist
regime that has expressly said they want
to kill and destroy the United States
multiple times. They've said that they
want to destroy Israel. Are we going to
allow them to become nuclear? Are we
going to allow them to build up their
ballistic missile program? Or are we
going to say, you know something,
there's no guarantee, but we're going to
hearken back to a story that is
3,000 years old, which has inspired
multiple stories throughout the world,
which is, you know what, there's no
guarantee. There's never been a
guarantee to defeat evil, but there is
one guarantee, if you don't stand up to
it, you're going to lose.
I'm in Dane.
You've made a point that is you've got
to filter out all the noise in a
fast-moving situation like this and try
and get to the reality of the movement
of military assets. You say deployments
don't lie, narratives do. The rest is
theater for markets, publics, and
gullible media. And of course, that is
often the case in every war.
Again, from where I sit
out here, it's not that I don't think
that the Iranians are a very bad regime.
They are and have been since they took
power in 1979. It's not that I'll lose
any sleep over the death of Ayatollah
Khomeini. He was an appalling human
being who terrorized his own people, who
sponsored terrorism all over the region,
largely aimed at Israel. So, I can
totally get all that.
Um
However,
launching such a full-throttle attack
on a country with 90 million people
where the regime clearly has a lot of
firepower to protect itself, 250,000
of the IRGC, you have half a million
paramilitaries, and nearly a million
regular army. But they've got a lot of
people around to enforce their will. And
so far, there's no sign of any public
uprising. There are a number of reasons
for that, not least of which bombs
flying around. Um but I just don't see
any sign
of a victory here.
I see a lot of bombs going off, a lot of
show of military might, but I also see
the Iranians winning the economic war
quite easily and quite devastatingly.
You know, I'm looking at the markets.
I'm looking at uh the oil production,
gas production. Uh and now I see Trump
in a message this morning
uh in which he talks about potentially
going after desalination plants in Iran.
Well, the first reaction of Iran to that
would be to go after desalination plants
in the Gulf states, which would be
utterly devastating. And for people who
don't quite grasp what that means,
you're talking about desert states that
rely on desalination plants for water.
If you get rid of those, they don't have
much drinking water left before they all
start dying. So, these are incredibly
bellicose, serious threats that Trump is
lobbing out all the time, whilst at the
same time saying, "Actually, you know
what? We're talking to them, and it
should be over soon."
I I just find all this not just
confusing, but borderline ridiculous.
Well, Piers,
March 2019, so that's about 7 years ago,
and on my podcast, um I talked about the
reason why Saudi Arabia went to war in
Yemen against the Houthis. And in that
uh conflict, I told In that podcast, I
said that one of the reasons
is that Saudi Arabia wanted to protect
above everything else
water desalination.
Because you see, during the Gulf War
between Iraq and Iran between 1980 and
1988, and I grew up in the Eastern
Province of Saudi Arabia at that time,
and I was from Bahrain.
Um so, I know all about like I mean the
situation um you know in the Gulf at
that time and how it was really
harrowing and
um really threatening. But at the same
time,
the Saudis realized that their water
desalination plants on the Gulf were
under threat from Iran in a future
conflict because since I grew up like I
mean I always hear about Iranian threats
from across the water. So, it's not
something new. So, the Saudis moved many
of these water desalination plants to
the west to the Red Sea even though it
will cost far more
uh you know in terms of economics of
doing it. However,
then 2014, the Iranians chased the
Saudis all the way into the southwestern
flank of their country, and they pushed
the Houthis into taking over the power
in Yemen, and you know after a bloody
civil war, and then they
absolutely start threatening water
desalination in the west of Saudi
Arabia. So,
you know Piers, the Iranians has been
threatening to close the Strait of
Hormuz since I was a 7-year-old child.
And that was 40 years ago. I mean, I
feel old now. And they've been
threatening the water desalination you
know of the Saudi Arabia and the other
GCC countries for 40 years. And they've
been threatening to attack energy
facilities. In fact, the attack against
energy facilities happened already at
the hands of the Iranian proxies in
September 2019 against Aramco, the
biggest But what they've been given what
they've been given here is license to do
it under the guise of retaliation
because They had the license from long
time ago, Piers. No, no, I'm not
disputing I'm not disputing what you're
saying. I'm just saying
I'm just saying they've always been
doing it. I understand but to to the
world what it looks like is that all
right, fair enough, you know, Iran's
getting bombed everywhere. The Israelis
are bombing their refineries. Why
shouldn't they bomb
other people's refineries? So, they're
using everything that's happening to
them as an excuse to do probably what as
you say they've wanted to do for a long
time but what they have worked out um is
that they can control
the global economy in a way that I think
the Americans have massively
underestimated and I think it's come as
a nasty shock. And that's the
>> I don't think you you you can't win a
war this way, Piers. I mean, this kind
of reasoning I'll give you an example.
Imagine there's you know, there's an
illegal arms dealer on your street,
right? And so, you call the FBI, you
call the police and they surround the
house and the guys inside the house
start shooting at you, right? So, what
are you going to say? Oh, you know, we
gave them an excuse to shoot at us. You
know, we gave them license to shoot at
us. No, if you're going to go after the
arms, then the guys are going to pick up
the arms that they're threatening and
you're going to use it. What's the
difference? Iran would have used this
anyway. They would have They would have
closed the Straits of Hormuz.
Piers, the difference is had we waited,
they would be closing the Straits of
Hormuz with a nuclear threat, with an
armed nuclear weapon. Could you imagine
the price of oil if there's a nuclear
Iran and they're crazy, right? I've got
ballistic missiles landing next to my
home with massive warheads which if one
of those landed in England, God forbid,
you know, and if it's undetected, it can
take out 50 blocks. If if we don't stand
up now, Iran's this isn't giving license
to them. This is trying to defeat them
and they're using whatever they have at
their disposal Well, then it but then it
comes down Okay, but then it comes down
to to how an impending threat uh you
feel Iran was posing and I am not
convinced as I wasn't by the argument
about Saddam Hussein back in 2003. I am
not convinced that there was an imminent
threat from uh these weapons in the way
that people have tried to sell it and I
think that's the problem. And I think
that you know
there are lots of bad regimes there are
lots of bad regimes around the world.
Well, there are there are lots of bad
regimes around the world
uh like North Korea that America does
not attack.
Right? Even though every argument you
would use against Iranians works equally
to the Iranians uh to the uh North
Koreans. So, there are reasons you don't
do this kind of thing.
>> Not at all. Not at all. Well, okay.
>> Not at all. Well, there's a okay. No
one's attacked North Korea. I'm I'm so
I'm sorry like I mean that's a false
equivalence because like I mean you know
comparing North Korea to Iran
first of all, North Korea did not
recruit 700,000
young men from across the region from
Iraq from Iran from Iran also from
Yemen from Lebanon from Syria. They did
not recruit all of these young people
into joining non-state actors terror
militias in order to destabilize their
own countries and then attack
neighboring countries with ballistic
weapons. They were not supposed to get
them in the first place. So, you see the
problem here is it's not North Korea is
just sitting in its own little box.
Perfect. You know at least it is
contained. It's a contained threat.
However, Iran refused to be a contained
threat. They expanded
>> true.
Uh let let me first of all, I think it's
a good equivalent for a number of
reasons. Yesterday, North Korea tested a
ballistic missile that can reach the
United States homeland.
They're not sitting in their own. But, I
also believe it's a it's a good
comparison because United States and the
four parties and then the six parties
spent many many years negotiating with
North Korea who convinced the world that
they weren't going to build a nuclear
weapon. We threw money at them, we threw
food at them, we threw
uh access to the international system,
and they continue to say, "No, we'll
never develop a nuclear weapon." Do you
think that Iran is not following that
same playbook? Of course it is.
Yeah, well, I'm I'm sure that's true.
Just hold fire panel for a moment. I
want to bring in another guest now,
General Sir Richard Shirreff. He's a
former NATO commander. General, welcome
to Uncensored.
Thank you for having me.
You've been pretty scathing about this.
You've called Operation Epic Fury
staggeringly arrogant. And you wrote in
the Daily Mail, "So, we are living
through, and as a lifelong soldier, I
don't ask this lightly, the outbreak Are
we living through the outbreak of World
War III? Certainly, I can't remember a
more perilous moment in geopolitics in
my lifetime, and I'm now 70."
I can't either. I'm actually 61 today,
and I can't
remember that either. As it's gone on,
we're a month in now, does your fear
about this escalating to that kind of
level, has that increased or or
decreased?
It's increased, without question.
I think the
the attack a month ago
was
launched without thinking through the
possible consequences.
I'm sure that
military commanders would have war-gamed
the death, the potential for closing the
Strait of Hormuz.
And would normally have taken sort of
action to prevent it, but clearly it did
not happen on this occasion. And I think
the assumption was made
that a lightning industrial-scale
aerial assault, such as we've seen,
would be enough to do what? I mean, we
didn't know. There's no clear design for
battle. There is no clear strategy.
There is no clear idea of how this war
ends.
I think and my concern is that we are
about to see
escalation
uh potentially putting troops on the
ground on the islands of the Strait of
Hormuz and or wherever.
Uh and then I think we have to take
account of the the linkages, the linkage
between what's going on in Ukraine with
Russia's genocidal war there, the fact
that Russia is now supplying drones and
targeting information
uh to the Iranians.
And I've no doubt there are further and
wider linkages. So, I think this is a
deeply deep deeply globally
destabilizing event. Not least, of
course,
it is completely not the global econom-
the potential for knocking the global
economy awry in a major way.
Let's not assume the Strait of Hormuz is
going to be opened anytime soon because
of America if the Americans land
amphibious troops in that
for whatever on that coastline,
this thing is going to run and run and
run. And we're going to be back into a
worse situation. You're probably not old
enough to remember 1973 and the oil
crisis then. Well, you might be, but you
know, we'll be back into that but times
10.
Yeah, I was eight actually then. But I I
do remember it vaguely, but I I you
know, I think the trouble is no one's
learned the lessons from history.
And I I I look at what's going on and I
think
you were the the Deputy Supreme Allied
Commander of Europe. You see some of the
rhetoric coming out of Donald Trump now.
Uh very bellicose and negative about
Europe, about NATO, about what he
perceives to be the lack of cooperation
uh here for Operation Epic Fury.
If you were still in your old job, what
what how would you be handling this?
Well, I think I would make the
assumption
that Donald Trump has pretty much
single-handedly torpedoed NATO as an
alliance. I let you have to understand
NATO is an alliance
which which flourished for
pretty nearly 80 years.
And it's based on trust. It's based on
common values. It's based on the
doctrine of collective defense that that
that that the alliance is there to
support an ally if attacked. The famous
Article 5.
From the moment we saw Trump two come
into power, we saw that Vance and
Heggseth announced very clearly that
America was not going to underwrite
European security. Now, I get that
because the Europeans, frankly, have
been freeloading from America for
decades. And so, there's a part, you
know, Europe has a part to play in this.
But then, move forward. The fact that 2
months ago, Donald Trump
threatened to attack the territory of a
NATO ally, Denmark, over Greenland.
Nobody has forgotten that. Europeans
will not forget that. And that is a
grotesque breach of trust that the lead
dog in the pack turns on the other a
smaller dog in the pack, as it were. So,
no surprise
that no NATO allies prepared to support
Trump in this particular ill-starred
mission.
No surprise for a start because it's not
a it's not a NATO operation. It NATO
does not look at color the territory
of of of of
of the Persian Gulf or the Arabian Gulf.
And absolutely, it does not support an
ally launching a an unprovoked, although
may you may argue that, but an attack
which which could well be construed as
illegal against a party that had not
attacked it. So, there's no way that
NATO should or could support it. But the
message for NATO now
is that NATO's got to pull its act
together. The European members of NATO
have got to get their act together,
recognize that yes, they have to
maintain links with America. And
certainly in the UK's case, the
intelligence and the military links are
much deeper than political. They are
built on frankly shoulder to shoulder
brothers and sisters in arms over many
years.
But that America as a an alliance ally,
a member of the alliance, is not going
to play a central part. So, Europe uh
Europe needs to step up to the mark and
drawing on Mark Carney's words from
Davos, develop and build an an alliance
based on the middle powers, which it can
do if it's prepared to make the
necessary sacrifices and European
leaders are prepared to show the
necessary leadership.
>> In one word, is the special relationship
done, over, kaput?
I I I
I think the special relationship is a
fantasy put about by my say so peers by
the media and politicians.
It died, if it ever was one, it died in
1956 at Suez.
And it's crazy to go on banging on about
the special relationship.
Couldn't be clearer. General Shirreff,
thank thank you very much for joining
me. I appreciate it.
Thank you for having me. Well, back to
my panel now. I'm pleased to say we've
been joined by the former CIA officer
John Kiriakou, who I'll come to in a
moment. John, welcome back to you.
General Kimmett, you were shaking your
head throughout a lot of that interview
with a
a British former general.
You didn't agree.
Well, a couple of things. He first said
that NATO has never operated in that
region. He's just absolutely wrong.
Operation Ocean Shield was conducted by
NATO as part of the counter-piracy
operations. So, they have been there
before. Second, the special relationship
is not something that simply
was a whim of the media. I lived that my
entire 30-plus years in the military. I
served side by side with Brits. We We
shared intelligence and we shared
foxholes. So, I think that special
relationship still exists.
And this notion about in his lifetime
he'd never seen something this whacked
up. For God's sakes, the 300,000 dead
and wounded at Gallipoli because of
British arrogance seems to me a fairly
good comparison. Uh so it just always
bothers me when somebody with a nice
Oxbridge accent comes on and starts
lecturing to the Americans.
You're sounding a little
>> And one last point, there is a solution
to the Strait of Hormuz, which is I do
not believe that Iran wants to fight
with the British, the French, the
Germans.
1981 to 1989, the United States escorted
Kuwaiti flag flagged and escorted
Kuwaiti tankers in and out of the Strait
of Hormuz. We can't do that this time
because the Americans are belligerents.
I wrote an article recently and the
title was, "Where are the allies?" So,
why aren't the allies like Britain and
France and Germany, who have far better
capabilities in countermeasure, and
they're not active belligerents in this
war, why are you not escorting the
tankers in and out? China would join you
as well. So, as everybody is ringing
their hands as the United States is
bringing the world economy to its knees,
why doesn't Britain and France and, you
know, God forbid, NATO take on that
mission?
Just out of interest, General, where
where were you educated?
Uh the United States Military Academy
and Bishop O'Connell High School, a
trade school in Arlington, Virginia.
You have a remarkably eloquent and
clipped American accent, I have to say.
I don't Not withstanding
>> the Brits for It's It's that special
relationship I've had with the Brits
over these years.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh John Kiriakou, welcome back to
Uncensored. Let's just talk for a moment
about the domestic jeopardy that I think
Donald Trump uh is risking here, and I
think it's significant. The polling is
terrible. Uh it's the first time I can
remember an an
uh armed forces at war, even if they're
not calling it that, which has not had
>> [clears throat]
>> the majority support of Americans. Gas
prices uh are skyrocketing. Food prices
are and will go higher because of the
issue with the fertilizer. You've got
the midterm elections coming. I mean,
General Kelly thinks he's already given
up that. I'm not sure that's how Trump
will be thinking, but certainly all the
polling again suggests that the
Republicans could lose both the House
and the Senate now if this continues the
way that it's going. Uh it just seems a
hell of a throw of a dice by Trump, and
I I'm increasingly thinking he's made a
massive miscalculation. What's your
view?
Oh, I think this is a disastrous
miscalculation.
Where do we even begin? You know, there
there's a very significant split right
now within the Republican Party here in
the United States. Yeah. There were a
lot of Republican voters who voted for
for Donald Trump because they believed
that he really was the no foreign wars
president. You might recall uh
February 14th, Valentine's Day 2016,
during a Republican debate in which
Donald Trump called George W. Bush a war
criminal for getting the United States
involved in uh in the war in Iraq.
And now all of a sudden, it's as though
it's John McCain's neoconservative
Republican Party again. It seems to me
that
that Trump
surrounded himself with some people like
Tulsi Gabbard, for example, and J.D.
Vance, who reportedly have been opposed
to these foreign interventions, but then
others like Marco Rubio, who is
sort of the the successor to the John
McCain uh
wing of that party, and the party and
the president himself don't know which
direction to go. Well, I think Lindsey
got I'm going to bring in I got I got
Lindsey Graham into that.
>> Lindsey Graham? I think he's been
extremely vocal.
>> right. Uh but what you really it it's so
true about the split in the party. I saw
Matt Walsh yesterday from the Daily Wire
making the point that almost every
Republican he's been talking to is
against this war. And he said it is
highly unusual when you have a
Republican administration that's gone to
war
um for Republicans to be as against it
as he is hearing personally anecdotally.
He thinks it's not showing up yet
properly in the polling. But I saw a
thing about enthusiasm for the midterms.
And I think the Republican enthusiasm
was down to like 60% and falling like a
stone, right? Which again
>> That's the danger. And I think that's
the kind of quiet That's the quiet voice
there of people saying, "We don't get
this. This guy The whole point of Trump
was he would not take us into foreign
wars, especially in the Middle East. And
definitely no boots on the ground." You
know, I do think if he commits boots on
the ground and it goes even half wrong
as many military strategists think it
could, then I think it's it's This
becomes his legacy. And again, I just
ask the question. And I would ask it to
I would ask it to the president myself
if he if he calls me. Um I would just
say, "Why did you do it now? I don't get
it."
Mhm.
I don't get it. I don't think I've ever
seen a gathering of more spineless
people in my entire life. I I This is
just simply it's like a vacuum, Pierce.
Like President Trump woke up one morning
and decided to go attack Iran because
Israel convinced them as if Iran does
not pose a nuclear threat, as if there's
no Hang on. Hang on. But Don, hang on.
Hang on. Hang on. Don, Don, Don, Don,
Don, Don, Don, Don, Don, Don, Don, Don,
Don, Rubio said when he was asked why
did America take preemptive action in
this way, he said because another
country bracket Israel had informed the
United States they were attacking Iran
and the expected result would be that
Iran would under that incident it would
then attack American interest and
therefore they had to get in first and
JD Vance has also said the same thing.
We're not making this up. This is
something coming out of the mouths of
the senior people in the administration.
Piers, why did why did Trump join the
12-day war at the end of the war?
Well, the 12-day war
>> been fighting alone for 11 and a half
days. Why did Trump
Why did Trump swoop in and take credit
for the particular reaction because he
believes that a nuclear Iran poses a
major threat? Sure, and we were told
okay
They've all said many different We were
told that threat was eliminated.
>> himself said We were told we were told
the 12-day war
>> Iran has killed No, let me answer.
thousands of Americans over the years.
He understands the American people. This
is their story. They don't need a reason
to understand that there's evil in the
world and to stand up for evil. And by
the way, the Brits are the ones who
taught us this. Sure. The the importance
of standing up against evil. Like what I
don't understand about any of the people
you brought on. Are we just then going
to surrender and let Iran just grow into
a nuclear-armed terrorism or does
anyone, including you, have another idea
of how to prevent this? Uh yeah, I think
the the honest answer about that is that
I I didn't think so.
Well, I've answered.
Well, I'm while we're doing that, I'm
going to take a look at my spine here.
Apparently it's going to disintegrate
[laughter]
Well, not all of you, but some of you.
But personally I think General Soleimani
is the most
I see three with spines, including
myself here. So you're you're one of the
But there's nothing there's nothing
Look, I don't think it's anything
particularly heroic or courageous about
launching the biggest military attack of
modern times with the with the most
overwhelmingly powerful military in
history
against Iran. That doesn't take
particularly
>> It's not to be hero. Who needs to be
hero? It's No, but I don't understand
what the impact I don't agree that there
was an imminent impending threat. I
think the imminent the only
Let me answer. The only imminent
impending thing was that Benjamin
Netanyahu told Trump he was going to
attack. We now know from Anthony
Blinken, a previous Secretary of State,
that he tried the same thing with Obama
and Biden, told them he was going to
attack, and then both Biden and Obama
said, "Well, we're not coming with you."
And then guess what? Israel didn't
attack. And that is why people believe,
when you add Rubio's comments, and
Vance's comments, that what happened
here is that Netanyahu railroaded Donald
Trump into going along with this in a
way that was actually rejected by Biden
and Obama, and that the actual threat,
which is we're going to do it anyway, he
probably wouldn't have done it anyway if
it wasn't for the Americans. So, you
know, history will tell us, I guess, the
answers to these questions, but it was
fascinating to me that Blinken said what
he said. Uh and as to where we are now,
how does it square? Surely, Dorian, you
must see the unbelievable risk of
committing ground forces to Iran to get
enriched uranium from deep under the
ground when we know how heavily
protected it is, and we know how cunning
the Iranians have so far been in the way
they've responded in this war. I I think
it's a terrifying potential escalation
that could lead to the deaths of many
many many Americans, right? And and I
say I say for what? Where is the
impending threat? Where was the
evidence? It takes me back to 2003.
Curious evidence. Well, hang on. You say
I'm spineless. Let me answer you about
spine. I was editor of the Daily Mirror
newspaper UK, one of the biggest selling
newspapers in the world at the time. I
took on my own government, Tony Blair,
the Labour government. We were Labour
supporting newspaper. I waged one of the
most ferocious campaigns against a war
in media history, and it failed. And we
know what happened in Iraq, because I
did not believe that there was the
evidence that Saddam Hussein had weapons
of mass destruction, or that he was
about to use them, or hit London in 45
minutes, or any of that And
you know what? It turned out very sadly,
I was right. And yet, 20 years later,
utter mayhem followed that illegal
invasion, as I saw it see it. So, I
don't think it's necessarily lacking in
a spine to say sometimes that these wars
are wrong, and they're fought on false
pretexts, and that the public is
entitled to stand up and say, "Not in my
name." That actually can often take more
courage than simply dropping a lot of
bombs on people.
Here's what we see that Iran has fired
now thousands of ballistic missiles,
including those that landed in Israel
and population centers. They fired two
ballistic missiles towards Diego Garcia,
which yes, had they not fired them to
the east, and they fired them to the
west, could have landed in London.
The warhead on a single ballistic
missile, if it's a ton and a half, do
you know what the impact zone is? It's a
hundred square blocks in London. What
would it take for you to acknowledge
that there's actually an imminent
threat? We have ballistic missiles
landing all over. At what point it when
the nuclear
the nuclear warhead is on the ballistic
missile and it's on its way to Israel,
do we then say, "Okay, this is an actual
threat?" Or do we stand up today against
a terrorist regime that has developed
proxies throughout the Middle East, that
created Hezbollah, created Hamas,
created the Houthis, took over the
United States Embassy in Iran, has
driven trucks and blown up thousands of
of hundreds of Marines, and have tried
MI5 has prevented 22 mass casualty
terror attacks in London since 2022.
What does it take? Okay, let me bring
John back John back in. John, your
response to that.
Where do we even begin? The The Iranians
have been reactive to this, not not
proactive. You know,
people people watch on the news the
what's happening in in Lebanon, in Gaza,
in the West Bank, in Syria. There has to
be a response. You can't just say,
"Well, you know what? We're an
existential threat to the Israelis, so
of course the Israelis are going to have
to bomb us." That's that's just not real
life. I can tell you in all the years
that I was in the CIA, no matter who the
Israeli Prime Minister was, every single
time an Israeli Prime Minister came to
Washington, no matter who the president
happened to be, the Israelis would say,
"Please help us bomb Iran. Please help
us bomb Iran. Please help us bomb Iran."
And the presidents always said, "No."
Until this one. I think that President
President Trump was duped by Benjamin
Netanyahu, and now we're in a war that
that is not ours
from the beginning and that we cannot
win. And this is another thing, too. My
own experience in the CIA and and at
some of the highest levels of
government, I was the executive
assistant to the CIA's Deputy Director
throughout the the Iraq War. There's
never an exit strategy. It's easy to
attack a country. It's easy to overthrow
a government, but then what do you do?
That's the hard part. Right. I mean I'm
indeed
that is the reality and that is why
Donald Trump was always so vocal, "I'm
not going to do this."
And yet here he is. He's doing it to the
biggest
the biggest
place he could possibly be doing it with
the greatest risk. And that's the bit I
don't understand. I I I think you're one
of the spineless three, so maybe you'd
like to respond to
>> No, he's got a spine. Oh, he's got a
spine. Okay, great.
>> We're down to two. Okay, we're down to
two spineless
people.
So, it's just the CIA guy and the guy
that rightly called the wrong illegal
wars. Got it.
Uh okay.
Look,
this war was going to happen by hook or
crook because at the end of the day, you
know, the Iran represented not the
perfectly
rational logical player in the
established global order. You know, in
this poker table, the global poker table
where the Russians, the Chinese, the
Brazilians, the Indians, the Europeans,
the Americans, you know, you see at the
end of the day, if you come to the poker
table and you try to cheat and undermine
everyone and they try like, you know, I
mean to be
absolutely loudish and brutish about it,
at the end of the day, you will be
escorted out of the premises
unceremoniously and then you'll be
you'll be terminated with extreme
prejudice. And this is the problem with
people who don't understand that the
Iranian threat was accumulatively
growing stronger and they more dangerous
as the years progress. Again, what is so
normative about Iran's politics in the
region? You have to understand that Iran
was expanding across the region, a
region that actually contain more than
50 plus percent of the world's
traditional energy reserves and that is
a threat to the global established
financial order that is backed by the
dollar as a reserve currency. You cannot
allow Iran to become the hegemon of the
entire region and then Iran can do
whatever it wants when it comes to
charging, you know, for the you know,
for the petrol with other currencies,
undermining the status of the US dollar
as a
uh the reserve currency of the world. If
you If you allow the Iran like when I
mean to have such unchecked power across
the region, it's going to be
tremendously I mean as always President
Trump said tremendously you know
dangerous to the status of the United
States you know financial system as the
financial system of the world. You know
and after this the fact that you cannot
like I mean basically say that Iran's
politics and in a rhetoric towards its
neighbors it's not just only Israel.
Some people always saying like it was an
existential threat towards Israel. Since
I was a child their entire rhetoric
wasn't just only about Israel and
America. It was also about Saudi Arabia.
It was about Kuwait. It was about the
UAE. The fact that they UAE trading with
Iran for more than 40 years and at the
first sign of trouble they threw more
than 2,500 ballistic missiles and drones
at the UAE. What does that tell you? It
tells you basically that their entire
plan their entire
military strategy was about hegemony
over the oil rich neighbors. It's simple
as that. They recruited so many
young men 700,000 Okay. to be part of
non-state actors you know illegal
non-state actors. In what world can we
tolerate that and the United States at
the end of the day if they want to you
know for the America first crowd
America cannot be
first at home
if it's not first abroad if it's not
first overseas because at the end of the
day the entire military the entire
economic system of the United
>> Okay. Look we've got to depends on its
being No I hear you. the hegemon of the
world and the guardian of the maritime
global established
>> empire.
>> But look you're making an assumption
that America's going to win this and I
think I think that's quite an assumption
to make right now. Yes it is but because
because at the end of the day is the
calculus of the firepower. Okay.
Okay, we'll see. We'll see.
We will
We will see
Yeah.
It's not just only firepower. At the end
of the day, what is a victory? Arabs
always say, you know, that victory is
just to be patient. Is your patience
outlast your enemies? Yeah.
But my guess is My guess There is no
economic patience in Iran anymore. My
guess is
My guess is that the Iranians will have
a lot more patience than Donald Trump.
We shall see. We shall see. You We will
see. All right. We'll have to wait and
see. I've got to leave it there, panel.
Thank you. Interesting debate. Thank you
very much indeed.
I'm pleased to say that I'm joined now
by Rudy Giuliani, the former New York
mayor and lawyer to President Trump.
Rudy, welcome back to Uncensored. How
are you, Piers? Oh, good. I've missed
you. You well? I do. Me too. You're
doing very well.
>> [laughter]
>> Look, We don't agree completely, but uh
but I I I really appreciate your ability
to uh
to really put out both sides. I want to
compliment you on what you did do
Fuentes. Oh, thank you. That was That
was one of the best interviews I've ever
seen, ever.
Oh, thank you. Particularly after
Particularly after um
he basically got that interview from uh
Tucker, where Tucker put him on his lap
and was patting his head.
>> [laughter]
>> Well, I just think I think the people
like Fuentes, you've got to challenge
them. That's the point. You can't You
can't give them a free run.
>> and you did it without being uh nasty or
>> Yeah.
You're like a good cross-examiner. I
would have hired you as an assistant
U.S. attorney. [laughter]
Do you know what? I sometimes think I
wish I'd been a lawyer.
Uh but that's for another for another
life, uh Rudy. Let's talk about Iran,
Rudy. You've said, I think, that Trump
is reasserting himself on the global
stage. Do you still feel that a month
in?
I do. I do. And you know, I I I have to
tell you, knowing him 40 years, I can
tell you that his views on on Iran
go back
long before
all I mean in the 1980s.
He's actually on record talking about
it, but I can remember having
conversations with him where we both
felt, particularly after the Marines
were hit
in in Lebanon,
we wondered why Ronald Reagan didn't
take him out
after after the hostage taking the
hostages, embarrassing the hell out of
the United States,
and then killing our Marines.
Um
I I think he
this this is like uh
This should have happened like 35 years
ago.
And a lot of people would be alive
today, and the world would be a lot
better. But we can we can't live
with nuclear weapons in the hands of an
irrational regime.
Um
This is not Putin. This is not Xi
Jinping. They're terrible people.
They're very evil, but they're not
irrational. They don't want to die.
The Ayatollah and the people around him
um
they're actually displaying the fact
that they do want to die.
The Ayatollah knew he was going to get
it. He sat there, and I think he thought
he was going to go up to paradise and
find his 72 virgins.
So, this really fits in what my
biggest hero used to say, Ronald Reagan.
Ronald Reagan used to say mutually
assured destruction is the way we kept
this world together for a long, long
time during the Cold War, but it's
immoral
because it rests on the fact that both
sides have to have a rational leader.
Mhm. You get a crazy man in either
either spot,
goodbye world.
And we got a crazy man
who wants to get nuclear weapons, has
already killed thousands of Americans.
Chants every week that he wants a death
to America.
I don't know how much more
how much more of a threat you have to
have uh But but given but given he's
being replaced, it it appears by his
son, although we haven't seen the son, a
supreme leader. And the son has now lost
his father, his mother, his wife, and
two of his kids reportedly, and may even
have died himself. We just don't know.
But But clearly the ideology hasn't
died. The IRGC remain in place. And I
just think, and General Kimmett just
shared this this uh concern, that if
America was to now commit ground forces
into Iran to try and get, for example,
the enriched uranium, it could be one of
the most dangerous operations American
forces have ever engaged in. And if as
you say you're dealing with unstable
people who don't mind dying for their
cause, does that not concern you,
really?
Of course it concerns me. Uh uh I mean,
when the when we lost our first soldier,
you say to yourself, is it worth it? And
now what, 13? Uh but the reality is
it worries me more
that we have a world in which uh a a uh
I mean, at one point Iran was a a a a
substantial power in the Middle East. It
looked like they had a uh
They had an empire across the northern
part of the Middle East. I mean, they
controlled Syria, they controlled
Lebanon.
They had uh three or four uh proxies
that
uh
were extremely dangerous. I mean,
Hezbollah was undefeatable at one point
that we we thought.
Uh so, to to let them
move back into that situation again,
puts the whole world in danger.
Uh
Why do you think they they they shot
that missile um
uh
that went What What did it go? 2,000,
2,500 mi? They want They wanted to show
Europe, you know, we can hit you at this
point.
And they've actually attacked the
Emirates more than they have Israel.
Right.
>> [laughter]
>> Which has to tell you
that they're that their aim here is
either
totally irrational or it's to be the
dominant power
in the Middle East.
>> oh, there's a third there's a third
way you could look at it which is it
shows you they're actually being quite
rational and quite cunning. They They
know they can't compete with America
stroke Israel militarily. They can't
compete with the military firepower in
terms of just numbers. But when it comes
to strangling the global economy by
closing [clears throat] the Straits of
Hormuz and when it comes to attacking
the Gulf states in the way they have
attacking refineries and tourist areas
and so on. You know, killing for now
stone dead the business models of those
states until this is over.
That shows a lot of rationality
actually. It's a rational response to
defending yourself when you can't do it
purely with military firepower, isn't
it? They've They've shown a cunning
which appears to have been
underestimated by America and Israel.
I'm not sure it was. I mean I think I I
I think I always thought
an action against Iran would be a major
war. It's a It's a country that's been
building up militarily. In fact, I think
had it been two or three years ago it'd
have been even worse. We've deteriorated
them a lot in the last two years. But I
mean the reality is that probably makes
sense at the beginning cuz that's what I
thought. I thought they were doing this
in order to get the Arab states to put
pressure on the president to call a
ceasefire.
But the reality is it's the opposite.
European countries want a ceasefire but
they want I mean they they would they
would surrender if I declared war on
them. And I'd be able to take them over.
I mean they're all a bunch of useless
cowards. But uh you really believe that,
Rudy? Oh my god, yeah.
I mean, they the
the prime minister in uh
your uh
your country, sad to say, sad to say uh
I have people from England telling me
you're going to be a Muslim country in
10 years.
I mean, there are the Anglican Church uh
the Catholic Roman Catholic Church is is
bigger in England now than the Anglican
Church.
And and and Charles uh Charles III might
be the Muslim monarch of uh of England.
I mean, they're taking over.
And they want to take over, and it's
their aim.
And and Iran is the fuel behind that.
You take out the Islamic Republic of
Iran, the whole thing moves in the other
direction.
>> Rudy, that only 5% of the UK is Muslim,
dude.
Uh it doesn't matter. I mean, they have
tremendous They have tremendous power.
How many mayor-alties do they have?
I mean, they watch the most the most
>> but
but this idea There's a lot of Americans
I
I'm increasingly concerned that a lot of
you guys seem to have this idea that
we're literally being overrun by
Muslims, and I I don't know where it's
coming from, cuz I live here.
I live in London. I don't get any
feeling I'm being overrun by Muslims.
Well, I mean, I was in London uh about a
year and a half ago, and it seemed to me
there were awful lot an awful lot of
women with veils on that I'd never seen
before.
And uh
you have you have debates over whether
Sharia law should be respected. Of
course, it shouldn't be respected.
Sharia law is a is a cult of death.
I mean, the Quran is a cult of death.
But Sharia law has no legal standing in
the UK.
Well, not according to a lot of reports
that I read in diff- in different parts
of of England, it actually dominates.
And Starmer seems to be very, very
affected
by uh by them politically. He seems to
want to make them happy, make them uh
contented. And certainly it seem to be
trying to make them English.
Uh nor do the French seem to be trying
to make them French.
Uh they're uh they're uh they're con-
they're contrary to
immigration and assimilation. They just
do the immigration part. Immigration and
then follow Muhammad.
What did Muhammad tell them to do? Take
over.
You're you're suggesting that all all
the millions of Muslims who live in the
UK have a kind of radical mindset. And I
would say back to you that that is
simply not the case. All the evidence
All the evidence suggests that that is
not the case. I don't I I don't think
they all have a radical mindset. In
fact, the majority of them don't. I I I
know Muslims in the United States. All
right. I've I've I've studied I've
studied the Quran. I've studied the
Quran. They seem to be very happy with
their situation. They don't want to
change. They don't want to change.
They're very very silent.
They are uh they are um
There's a very very um
excessive
uh militaristic form of uh the Muslim
religion, which is justifiable based on
the literal words of the Quran.
And then the rest of the Muslims are
very silent. Uh you rarely hear an
objection to the horrible things that
they do.
And very often you hear a defense of it
from the It's very hard to get Muslims
to stand up to the atrocities
that they have that they that that they
commit. And it there's a defensiveness
that's extraordinarily dangerous.
Reminds you of old uh Germany. Certainly
all of Germany weren't Nazis. They just
were afraid, and they were defensive.
And wouldn't stand up to it. Uh that is
that is uh
a significant problem in the in the
Muslim world. And it's beginning to
change in in uh in the Arab countries.
You also can't discount the fact that
what you have going on between Iran,
Persia,
and uh the and the Saudi Arabian desert
is a a 1,500 year
2,000 year war between the Persians and
the Arabs.
I mean, they despise each other deep
down.
Now, what what happened and why your
theory that it was very rational doesn't
work is because the Arab countries are
now telling Trump, "Don't end this
and leave them leave them there."
Because to leave them there is just to
kick this down the road. If they're
going to do this to Emirates now,
if they get more powerful, uh they'll do
even worse.
So, uh if if I were if I were the emir,
I would be very much in favor of every
anything and everything that gets this
theocracy over with.
And I think it's possible to uh to do
it. I don't think they're as powerful as
they appear to be.
I think that we've done tremendous
damage to them.
God knows we we don't know because most
of the press and most of the reporting
is very much against us. To suggest that
they're winning this war like the
Economist did is absurd.
You're not winning a war when you've
lost thousands and we've lost 13. I
mean, it's absurd.
Uh and where you've taken more people
out in the Emirates than you have in
Israel.
Uh the reality is we don't know how much
longer it has to go and we don't know
when they're going to break, but we have
them going in that direction.
And we it's going to take an awful lot
to get them back there again if we have
some other president has to do it. Well,
Rudy, I I Listen, I There are many
people that share your view about this.
I have serious misgivings about this I
know you do and I you you're entitled to
and there are and I think it's it is a
it is a a difficult war is always
Yeah.
>> War is always very, very difficult and
um it always should be debated. But, you
know what? I will always I will always
allow people to have a completely
different view to me to come on and air
their views as you've done. And And
that.
>> And I and I
there there are times in which I sit
back and and uh
run through my head all all the things
that you're saying. I don't think it's a
I don't think this is an obvious That's
why I hate people who describe
themselves as interventionists or
isolationists.
You shouldn't be either. I mean, it
really depends it depends very much on
how much danger is there to you. And I
think, you know, maybe we evaluate that
danger differently. Yeah.
Rudy, I've got to leave you there. But
great to have you back on Uncensored.
Thank you very much. Al- always good to
be with you, Piers. And I tell you your
analysis is is is terrific. I appreciate
it. Thank you very much.
>> a real service. Thanks, Rudy.
Take care.
Piers Morgan Uncensored is proudly
independent. The only boss around here
is me. If you enjoy our show, we ask
only one simple thing. It's subscribe on
YouTube and follow Piers Morgan
Uncensored on Spotify and Apple
Podcasts. And in return, we will
continue our mission to inform,
irritate, and entertain. And we'll do it
all for free. Independent Uncensored
media has never been more critical, and
we couldn't do it without you.